James Isnor

resume.isnor.ca
linkedin.com/in/isnor/

I have a bachelor's degree in computer science and more than 8 years of software development experience. I've spent my entire career learning, becoming a jack-of-all-trades in the backend, and for the last few years I've been honing my cloud architecture and Golang skills. I am very passionate about writing excellent quality code, tests, and documentation, and I have a versatile DevOps background - I've built CI/CD pipelines (codepipeline, jenkins, gitlab, and github actions), written terraform modules from scratch for both microservices and full platforms, written hundreds of unit tests, integration tests, and load tests, and built monitoring and analytics dashboards.

Work Experience

Software Development Consultant

MadHive

Mar 2022-Oct 2023

Reporting and Analytics team

New York, USA (Remote)

- Led a team of 5 Golang engineers, vastly improving quality standards and providing support, process, and planning on an AdTech team
- Built APIs (Golang) for a reporting and analytics platform that queries hundreds of terabytes of data to provide customer insights
- Refactored thousands of lines of handler code to be test-driven and wrote 100+ tests
- Rewrote and optimized over two dozen BigQuery queries, reducing customer page-load times by more than half
- Created all of the documentation for reporting services, from high-level Confluence pages to README to API spec
- Created a testing library for all of the Golang engineers to more easily facilitate test-driven-development for REST APIs

Senior Software Developer

Redspace

2019-2022

Bedford, Canada

- Designed and built a cloud solution from scratch that assists in improving ad quality for ViacomCBS, handling 8-15k requests/second and responding to more than 99.99% within 50ms.
- Wrote a Terraform module to provision the infrastructure for a real-time video streaming platform that included among others, a VPC, NATs, EFS, CodePipeline, ECS, and ALB
- Migrated traditionally deployed applications (Chef, Jenkins, EC2 instances, ELB, and auto-scaling) to a serverless architecture using Docker, ECS, and Kubernetes.

Software Developer

Nielsen

2017-2019

Toronto, Canada

- Built cloud solutions on AWS using CloudFormation.
- Created various internal tools and services, such as a distributed load testing service using AWS lambda and Puppeteer and an alerting system using Python, Slack, OpsGenie, API Gateway, and AWS Lambda.

Junior Software Developer

Sentrant Security

2016-2017

Fredericton, Canada

- Built and maintained a collection service (Java, Scala) responsible for ingesting and queueing (Kafka) data for our analytics platform.
- Wrote unit, integration, and load tests

Lead Game Developer

First Mobile Education

2015-2016

Fredericton, Canada

- Designed and built mobile educational games from concept using Unity and C#
- Wrote game code for play controls, world interactions, physics, and more

Education and Certifications

• B.Sc. Computer Science, Mount Allison University, Canada.

2011-2015

Technologies and Languages

• Languages: Go, Python, Scala, SQL

• Technologies: AWS, terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, git

• Other: DevOps, CI/CD, REST, Agile

References

References are available from my most recent projects; please send an email requesting their information.